A Guide to the Correspondence of John F. Herrity, 1975-1988
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Correspondence of John F. Herrity, 1975-1988
The Library of Virginia
1170676-1170715
39 cu. ft.
Fairfax County (Va.) Board of Supervisors
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
These items came to the Library of Virginia in shipments of court papers from Fairfax County under the accession number 42347.
Biographical Information
John F. Herrity was a member of the Fairfax County (Va.) Board of Supervisors as a representative of the Springfield district from 1971 to 1975. He served as chairperson of the Fairfax County (Va.) Board of Supervisors from 1976-1988.
Scope and Content
Correspondence of John F. Herrity - Board of Supervisors Chairperson, 1971-1988, includes correspondence from his time as represenative of the Springield district from 1971 to 1975 and as Chairperson from 1976-1988.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged
Index Terms
Persons:
Herrity, John F.
Corporate Names:
Fairfax County (Va.) Board of Supervisors
Subjects:
County officials and employees--Virginia--Fairfax County
Geographical Names:
Fairfax County (Va.)--History--20th century.
Genre and Form Terms:
Correspondence--Virginia--Fairfax County; Local government records--Virginia--Fairfax County
Contents List
- Chairperon's Correspondence, 1972-1983., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1170695)
  Birdie Creek; Bradley Acres; Burk Manor; Chatilly Mews; Circle Property Inc.; CMI Option Agreement Covent Gardens; Fairfax Apartments Housing; Franconia Commons; George Mason Grave Site; The Green^^Guardian Construction Co.; Lordon Properity; Oak Creek; One University Square: Office Bldg. The Overlock; Tree Farm Resolution
- Chairperon's Correspondence, 1972-1983., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1170696)
  EDA; Federation; Federal Revenue Haring; Ferguson; Gasoline Shortage
- Chairperon's Correspondence, 1972-1983., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1170697)
  Chairman's Council; River Towers Condo Conversion; Condo Townhouse/Ordinance; Disclosure Bill; Drunk Driving Forum, 1982; Dulles, Misc
- Chairperson's Correspondence, 1972-1983., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1170698)
  Norton, Mrs. Riverbend Condo Project; Dulles Misc; Dulles Industrial Park; Consumer Protection Dulles Misc. Impact Study; Evermay; Executive Pay Plan; Supporters; Cable TV Supporter
- Chairperson's Correspondence, 1972-1983., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1170699)
  Goodman Rezoning; Growth; Group Home; Halfway House; Handicapped Group Home; Health System Agency; Heritage Wood North; Human Reston
- Chairperson's Correspondence, 1972-1983., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1170700)
  Easement; Lake Braddcok;Key Center Playground; Lee District;Carter Glass Library;Belmont Bay Mason Neck;Mandates for Lacal Govt's; I-66 Landfill; JLARC; Job Training Partnership Act; Handicapped Amendment to Human Rights Ordinances
- Chairperson's Correspondence, 1972-1983., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1170701)
  I-66; Human Services Reorganization; Human Rights; Potomac River Basin Testimony; Low Flow Retirement; Police General; Police (L.E.A.A. Grants & Compliance etc.)
- Correspondence, 1972-1983., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1170702)
  Shirley Highway Ramp Metering; Sexual Assault; Recycling Commuter Bus; Reston; Braddock Road Task Force; Privacy Act-Medium of International Act; Metro- accelerated payment for rapid rail; Metro Bus; Metro 1974-75 Deficits Hassel ;Washington Metropolitan Area Transit; 1976 UOSA - Upper Occoquan Sewer Agreement; Occoquan
- Chairperson's Correspondence, 1972-1983., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1170703)
  Citizen/Org. Letters to Board for/against Downsizing; Park Award Chairman - John F. Herrity; Park Authority: Police- Teamster Union; Mobile Homes; National Election Accelerator Center; Northern Va. Bd. Of Realtors; Northern Va. Regional Park Authority Cameron Run Park Board Nuclear- Resolution passed May 3, 1982; UOSA; Industrial Cost/Recovery Systems & Waste Water Damage Ordinance
- Chairperson's Correspondence, 1972-1983., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1170704)
  Taxes and Budget: Circle Woods Public Housing Providence District; Hillwood Square; Greater Washington- Research Center Material; Memco & Bradlees; McNama Report; McNARAMA/ Dearborn^^Airport: Mason Neck- Ft. Belvoir
- Chairperson's Correspondence, 1972-1983., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1170705)
  Water; City of Fairfax V/WMATA: Va. Hills Echo; Assessment Budget Taxes; Assessment Real Estates^^Newspaper Articles on Water; Water Shortage Letters'Water-Low Flow; Waste Supply Task Force^^PL-566; Water Authority 1975 Capital Improvements;WCW Lawsuit
- Chairperson's Correspondence, 1972-1983., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1170706)
  Task Force on Family Violence and Task Force on Victim Crime; U-006Maury Heights Storm Outfall General; U-006 Maury Heights Sisson Commuter Tax-1078; Child Care-1981; Child Care-1982 Commuter Tax; Child Care-1985; Child Care- Misc Pamphlets; Child Care-1983; Child Care-1984^^Child Care Newsletters; Children World; Voices; Homeless/Shelter; BZA Church Shelters
- Chairperson's Correspondence, 1972-1983., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1170707)
  Handicap-Day Care; Housing; Accessory Units-Propose Rezoning; Harwood House; Educational Issue- Literacy; Budget-1983; Budget-1980 FY '81; Budget Information- general, assessments FY '82; Assessments-Property; Internal Audit
- Chairperson's Correspondence, 1973-1982., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1170708)
  General Assembly 1974; General Assembly- Jack's mini legislative packet for 1974; Small Claims Testimony- Campaign Contributions Testimony; 1974 General Assembly Legislative Program; Testimony on Contribution Bill; Delegate Vincent F. Callahan; Legislative Affairs 1974- Press Clippings; General Assembly- 1974 Legislative Bulletin - VA Assoc. City; General Assembly 1973; 1973 Legislative Package^^General Assembly 1975; General Assembly1976; General Assembly 1975 Jack's Leg Packet Fairfax Water Authority (HB1212) SCC Control; Members- Va. Legislature; Va. Legislature Calendar; Solid Waste^^Circuit Breaker; Small Claims Court; Time $ Phase Growth; Builder's Fine Homeowner's Warranty^^Political Reform Fairfax City Legislature Pkg. Status Report; Tenant- Landlord; FIRE- High Rise^^General Services; Fire ;Hospital- South Hospital- 2; Fairfax; Mr. Vernon Hospital; Police-2; Hospital- Commonwealth; Community Action Agency; Highway FAUS
- Chairperson's Correspondence, 1973-1982., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1170709)
  Alexandria Sanitation Authority; Environmental Management; HEALTH: Mt. Vernon Hospital^^Health 1967 Bond Issue; Mt. Vernon Hospital Law Suit; Water Authority; Rainwater Dump^^Crippen Landfill; Courthouse Cafeteria; Herndon; Park Authority- Nottoway Park; Consumer Congress^^I-66 Citizens Adv. Comm.; Fire Services; Burke Volunteer Fire Department; Fort Hunt Fire; Schools^^Wolftrap SE
- Chairperson's Correspondence, 1973-1982., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1170710)
  Microwave Tower; 911 Emergency Phone Number; Water; Dtente Manor- McLean (new Nursing Concept); Fairhaven Conservation Plan; Vale Swim & Tennis Club- Clark's Landing; Woodburn Assoc, Rezoning Application; Shadowood Condos (Mrs. MacKay); Hospice; Holmes Run Woods & Crossing^^Fairfax County Courier; Cedeno; Purchasing Audit; Performance Bond; Ekmekjian Family School problem; Teachers' pay raises; School Boundaries
- Chairperson's Correspondence, 1973-1982., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1170711)
  School Boundaries Conts.; Schools- Constit. Corres. 1978; Lake Braddock Secondary School 1977^^Schools Year Around; Schools 1976; Schools: Reston High School; School General; Schools- Student on School Board; Schools- Vocational Education; Disco-Springfield Teen Center; ETA Teen Center-Westspringfield; Affirmative Action Plan
- Chairperson's Correspondence, 1973-1983., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1170712)
  School Boundary Study; Bilingual Education; Additive Free Lunch; School Problems Schools: Buses^^School- Bus Transportation 1979- Proposed Change/Constit.; School- Closing on Election Day^^Schools Legislative Prg. 1982; Schools- Closings (Belvedere School); Schools- Closings (Wilton Woods)^^Schools- Closings/ Use of Space for County Facilities; Schools- Closing- School for Contemporary Education Lease Space; Reutilization of Closed Schools; Surplus School Prop.; School Lincolnia School Use/ Central Fairfax Services; Schools/Enterprise Learn Group; Schools- Handicapped- Kindergarten Legislation; Education- House Bill 574; Mandated Kindergarten; Schools- Legislation; Martin Luther King Holiday; Schools-No Smoking Policy; Schools- Misc, Policy, etc.; Schools/ Gifted and Talented Program; Music Instruction Private in Public Schools; School- Sex Education 1980 Curriculum; Schools: County Sex Education Policy; Sex Educating News Clippings; Schools- Tax Credit Tuition; Schools Teachers- FEA; Schools- Handicapped; School Budget- FY '76
- Chairperson's Correspondence, 1973-1982., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1170713)
  TRI-FAM; Fairfax Hospital; Library for Lorton Area (Engleside Closing); Revenue Sharing; Comprehensive Health; Com/Aging; Park Authority; HSA-1981; Lake Accotink City of Fairfax^^School Bd. Publication Supergram: Press Release; Summary; Schools- School Budget; FEA^^Teacher's Salary-Constituent Letters
- Chairperson's Correspondence, 1973-1982., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1170714)
  Staffing of Area Office; Electoral Board; Oak Creek Townhouse Development; Plus: Interim Develop^^Plus: Lawsuits; Plus: Miscellaneous; Land Use Moratorium; Plus: Adequate Public Facilities^^Plus: Building Ban (Burke Station Swim Club; '74 Building Ban- Letters; Planning- Plus; Allman Case^^CEDENO (Personnel); Alexandria-City of; Animal Commission; Annandale Chamber; Annandale Christian Comm.; Arlington County 2; Elderly: District Home; Health: South County Hospital Mount Vernon
- Chairperson's Correspondence, 1973-1982., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1170715)
  Fall Church City; NVTC: 1974 Audit; Mobile Crisis Unit; Legislative Program 1978-79; General Assembly Session 1981;Homeowners Assoc.-Tax Exempt Newington Comm. Assoc.; Great Fall Library
- Chairperson's Correspondence, 1975-1987., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1170676)
  Record file code #10000- # 24500
- Chairperson's Correspondence, 1978-1987., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1170677)
  Record file code #24511- # 34120
- Chairperson's Correspondence, 1978-1988., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1170678)
  Record file code #34120-#34159
- Chairperson's Correspondence, 1978-1987., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1170679)
  Record file code #34160- #35232
- Chairperson's Correspondence, 1978-1987., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1170680)
  Record file code #35232- #37002
- Chairperson's Correspondence, 1978-1987., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1170681)
  Record file code #37010-#38240
- Chairperson's Correspondence, 1978-1987., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1170682)
  Record file code #38280-#45420
- Chairperson's Correspondence, 1978-1987., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1170683)
  Record file code #50000-#66310
- Chairperson's Correspondence, 1978-1987., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1170684)
  Record file code #67001-# 94000
- Chairperson's Correspondence, 1978-1987., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1170685)
  George Mason University: I-95 Energy Resource/Recovery; Facility, CAAD- Transfer of National & Dulles Airport; Fairfax Co. SHARE INC.; "Kid s for Kids against Hunger-Ethiopia:Animal Control; Cat Ordinances;Mr. Selim et al; Letters from Superintendent; School- Mr. Robert Spillane
- Chairperson's Correspondence, 1978-1987., Extent: 1 box. (Box 117086)
  Abortion; Flex Time; Gas Line Brake; CRON Files; 1978 Dec. - 1979 Dec.; 1980 Jan.-Dec
- Chairperson's Correspondence, 1978-1987., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1170687)
  CHRON Files 1981-1985, 1987
- Chairperson's Correspondence, 1978-1987., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1170688)
  Teacher salaries 1985;Seat Belts- School Buses 1985;West ford Public Housing; Schools 1984 H Hunt High School; Gem Spring 2; Newington Station; Fair Housing Act- 1980; Housing Assistant Plan 1979-81; Fair Housing Authority-Audit Report Herrity Statement 1-26-8;Housing: low - moderate income; Apartments^^Coventry 1981 (5 additional folders); Fair Housing Board; Bett & Housing; Federal Government vs. County 1977 H.U.D
- Chairperson's Correspondence, 1978-1987., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1170689)
  Fairfax Redeveloping and Housing Authority; Revisions to Groveton Redevelopment. Plan^^Group Home-Handicapped Hollin Hills-Elderly Housing; Hollywood Manor; Jefferson Village 1984^^Regency 11; Public Housing; Wolftrap Citizen Association H.U.D.; Woods of Fairfax; Public Hearing^^Block Grant Funds; Imperial Housing; Housing Monthly Reports; Wooding Nightingale; Industrial Development Bond; Low Moderate Income Housing-McLean House II; Toth - School Board Moon Case^^O Day Drive; Community Development Block Grant; Susan School-Consolidation; GASOHOL
- Chairperson's Correspondence, 1978-1987., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1170690)
  GASOHOL; Display Ban Ordinance; Wolftrap; Wolftrap Fire 4/82; Small and Minority Business; Enterprise Seminar; Mother Jones; Nudity Ordinance; Nudity Obscenity (Book Store);Pensacola Economic Development; Refugee Funding; Drinking Age to 21 (1983)
- Chairperson's Correspondence, 1978-1987., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1170691)
  Public Safety Academy & Work Training Proposal; Drug Paraphernalia 5B-158; Drunk & Driving Phony I.D's; Fairfax Fair; Anti Crime Commission; Breakfast Industries & Schools; Anti-Catholic Literatures-Pornography; Board Matters; Vanpools; Substance Abuse- Drunk Driving; Straight, Inc.-DWI; DWI
- Chairperson's Correspondence, 1978-1987., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1170692)
  Transp-Task Force; Crossbow; Uranium; Gasoline- Alcohol (Gasohol); Oakerest- C. Randell Counterence Center; Zoning Ordinance Amendment; Message Parlor Ordinance; TTA; Refugee Funding; Justice Department-Discrimination Suit
- Chairperson's Correspondence, 1978-1987., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1170693)
  1983, 1986-1987 Receipt Contribution
- Chairperson's Correspondence, 1978-1987., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1170694)
  Receipts Contributions